const politicalQuestions = [
  //    new Array(totalPages).fill(new Array(questionsPerPage).fill(null))
  {
    question: "_____ was formely referred to as NyasaLand.",
    options: ["Congo", "Seychelles", "Madagascar", "Malawi"],
    correctAnswer: 3, //"Malawi",
    id: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Nigeria gain her independence on October 1st ____?",
    options: ["1914", "1960", "1956", "1963"],
    correctAnswer: 1, //"1960",
    id: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "____ is the proponent of system theory",
    options: ["K. Marx", "G. Almond", "D. Easton", "H. Lasswell"],
    correctAnswer: 2, //"D. Easton",
    id: 3,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The partioning of Africa and sharing of her resources among European powers was done at ...",
    options: [
      "UN Conference",
      "International Conference",
      "Berlin Conference",
      "WWII",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 2, //"Berlin Conference",
    id: 4,
  },
  {
    question: "The United Nations(UN) is preceded by which body?",
    options: [
      "OAU(Organization of African Unity)",
      "WHO(World Health Organization)",
      "European Union (EU)",
      "League of Nations",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 3, //"League of Nations",
    id: 5,
  },
  {
    question: "The commonwealth countries are colonized by?",
    options: ["Britain", "Germany", "Russia", "France"],
    correctAnswer: 0, //"Britain",
    id: 6,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Isabela was the first colony in the New World founded by the ____ Empire",
    options: ["British", "German", "Russia", "French", "Spanish"],
    correctAnswer: 4, //"Spanish",
    id: 7,
  },
  {
    question: "_____ propounded the theory of souls",
    options: ["Weber", "Plato", "Aristotle", "Tacitus"],
    correctAnswer: 1, //"Plato",
    id: 8,
  },
  {
    question: "Which year is the Berlin conference?",
    options: ["1885", "1884", "1997", "1202", "2024"],
    correctAnswer: 0, //"1885",
    id: 9,
  },
  {
    question:
      "If system theory is to D. Easton, ______ to Communication theory",
    options: ["Rostow", "L. Pye", "B. Powell", "K. Deutsch"],
    correctAnswer: 3, //"K. Deutsch",
    id: 10,
  },
  {
    question: "Leopold Senghor was the first president of _______",
    options: ["Burkina-Faso", "Congo", "Mali", "Senegal"],
    correctAnswer: 3, //"Senegal",
    id: 11,
  },
  {
    question: "All these countries are Portuguese colony except.",
    options: ["Madagascar", "Guinea-Bissau", "Angola", "Mozambique"],
    correctAnswer: 0, //"Madagascar",
    id: 12,
  },
  {
    question:
      "'Same taxi, different driver', this was the view of the _____ people after the change of government from Tolbert to Samuel Doe.",
    options: ["Nigeria", "Zambia", "Angola", "Liberia"],
    correctAnswer: 3, //"Liberia",
    id: 13,
  },
  {
    question:
      "'Ordinary people see the state as a hostile force to be evaded, cheated or defeated as circumstances permit.' The above is the view of ______ on the plunging of the Africa resources by the government and their cronies.",
    options: ["C. Ake", "M. Meredith", "R. Greene", "W. Rodney"],
    correctAnswer: 0, //"C. Ake",
    id: 14,
  },
  {
    question:
      "United States war of independence was fought from _____ to ______.",
    options: ["1775,1783", "1775,1784", "1777,1804", "1925,1936"],
    correctAnswer: 0, //"1775,1783",
    id: 15,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The United States war of independence was an insurrection by compatriots in the 13 colonies to gain independence from ______",
    options: ["France", "Netherlands", "Britain", "Spain"],
    correctAnswer: 2, //"Britain",
    id: 16,
  },
  {
    question: "The Nigeria civil war was between ______ to ______.",
    options: ["1963,1966", "1967,1970", "1968,1970", "1967,1971"],
    correctAnswer: 1, //"1967,1970",
    id: 17,
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ and ______ countries were formally referred to as Rhodesia before their independence.",
    options: [
      "Zambia, Zimbabwe",
      "Malawi, Mozambique",
      "Seychelles, Mauritania",
      "Guinea-Bissau, Equatorial Guinea",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 0, //"Zambia, Zimbabwe",
    id: 18,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Bunyoro-Kitara kingdom regarded as one of the most powerful Kingdom in Central and East Africa from 13th century - 19th century can be found in the present day ______",
    options: ["Rwanda", "Cameroon", "Tanzania", "Uganda"],
    correctAnswer: 3, //"Uganda",
    id: 19,
  },
  {
    question: "All these countries are West Africa countries except _______",
    options: ["Nigeria", "Ghana", "Cameroon", "Burkina-Faso"],
    correctAnswer: 2, //"Cameroon",
    id: 20,
  },
  {
    question: "The longest serving head of state in Africa is _______",
    options: [
      "Isaias Afwerki ",
      "Teodoro Obiang",
      "Yoweri Museveni",
      "Paul Biya",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 1, //"Teodoro Obiang",
    id: 21,
  },
  {
    question:
      "King Mswati III is the only ruling absolute monarch in africa. He rules over ______ country/kingdom.",
    options: ["Eswatini", "Lesotho", "Ethiopia", "Eritrea"],
    correctAnswer: 0, //"Eswatini",
    id: 22,
  },
];

export default politicalQuestions;
